Finding Aid for David V. Tinder Collection of Michigan Photography, County File, Wayne County, 1865-1985
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
- David V. Tinder collection of Michigan photography, County File, Wayne County, Box 19 (Box 19)
  - 299. [Post mortem-funeral displays, ca. 1910s-1930s], 14 photographs
Agdan Photographic.; Alliance Commercial Photo Co.; Alvord & Co.; American Commercial Photo Co.; Arthur Studio.; Arthur, Edward J.; Babas Studio.; Baker Art Studio.; Baker Studio.; Baker, Chas. R.; Ball, Lyman L.; Ballaun Studio.; Baron, Herman.; Blanchard, Issac H.; Bleibel, Gustav.; Bonish Studio.; Bowles, Esther A., Mrs.; Brown & Co.; Burose, Herman.; Charles Hopp & Co.; Cheff, Edmund Archael.; Club Photos Inc.; Commercial Photo Service Co.; Cousins Art Studio.; Craine, Benjamin H.; Davison Photo Studio.; Deluxe Theatrical Studio.; Detroit Edison Co.; Detroit News Staff.; Fotografia Italiana (G. Lanni & Co.); General Motors Photographic Section.; Harbican Studio.; Hayes, Clarence Messenger.; Hediger, James D.; Hillmer, Davis B.; Hoffman Studio.; Hoffman, Clarence L.; Holcombe & Metzen.; Holgate Studio.; Howie, George William.; Hughes, John Wesley.; Huntington & Clark.; Jackson, Harvey C.; James, Langford P.; Jones, J. F.; Lazarnick, Nathan.; Litynski, Walter E.; Litynski-Jakubowski Co.; MacGregor and Company.; Manning Bros.; Mazur, Anthony; McMichael, A.G.; Merz, Charles J.; Metropolitan Art Studio.; Mirecki, Albert J.; Modernistic Photo Studio.; New Chene Studio.; P. Pieronek Studio.; Phelps, C.A. (New Castle, IN); Pipp, Frank H.; Poli, Faustino G.; Pollard, C.H.; Rembrandt Studios.; Rentschler, Andrew.; Rentschler's Studio.; Rochowiak, Stanley A.; Rotch, Otto.; Salter, Al.; Smart Set Studio.; Smith Brothers Commerical Photographers.; Sowinski, Joseph.; Spellman, Delmar Driscoe.; Spencer & Wyckoff.; Spooner & Wells, Inc.; Stone, Frank H.; Tiffany Photographic Studio.; Tomlinson, Frank N.; Wiederhold, John A.; Wright, Fred G.; Ziawinski Bros.; Ziawinski, Felix.; Ziawinski, Joseph.
Genre Terms:
Clippings.; Cyanotypes.; Documents.; Ephemera.; Pamphlets.; Photocopies.; Photographic prints.; Photomechanical prints.; Postage stamps.
Photographer Index A complete list of photographers represented in the Wayne County series of the Tinder collection.
David V. Tinder Collection of Michigan Photography.
For visual iconography of Detroit up to the age of photography, see Brian Leigh Dunnigan, Frontier Metropolis. Wayne State University Press, 2001.
Other similar resources include the photograph collections at the Burton Historical Collection, Detroit Public Library, the Detroit Historical Society Museum, the Walter P. Reuther Library, Wayne State University, the Benson Ford Research Center, and the Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.
The Detroit Historical Society has on their website a useful timeline of Detroit history.
Tinder, David V. Directory of Early Michigan Photographers. This reference work contains biographical information about virtually every known commercial and significant amateur photographer in the state of Michigan from the first known appearances in the 1840s into the early twentieth century.